Finding Aid for Blodgett Family papers, 1872-1953
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Blodgett Family papers 1872-1953, 1884-1934
Blodgett family.
851371 Aa 2; AC
Family of Delos A. Blodgett, his son John W. Blodgett, and his grandson John W. Blodgett, Jr., residents of Grand Rapids, Michigan and owners of a series of logging companies active in Michigan, Mississippi, California, Oregon, and Vancouver Island. Correspondence, journals, cash books, ledgers, and maps of family businesses, including the Blodgett Company, Wright-Blodgett Company, Michigan-California Lumber Company, Michigan Timber Company, Hill-Davis Company, and Tidewater Timber Company; also personal correspondence and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
33 linear feet
43 oversize volumes
12 oversize folders
The bulk of the collection was donated by John W. Blodgett, Jr. (donor 4302 ), in 1965. A further accession was received in 1990 from the Grand Rapids Public Library (donor 767 ) which had been given the materials by Mrs. John W. Blodgett, Jr.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Blodgett Family of Grand Rapids, Michigan were owners of a series of logging companies in Michigan, Mississippi, California, Oregon, and Vancouver Island. Members of the family included Delos A. Blodgett, his son John W. Blodgett, and his grandson John W. Blodgett, Jr.
Chronology of the Blodgett family
1825 Delos A. Blodgett born, Otsego County, N.Y.
1848 Delos A. Blodgett moved to Michigan and began lumber business
1851 Delos A. Blodgett moved to Hersey, Mich.
1859 Delos A. Blodgett and Jennie S. Wood married
1860 John W. Blodgett born, Hersey, Mich.
ca. 1870 Delos A. Blodgett began logging in Osceola, Missaukee, and Clare Counties
1871 Blodgett & Byrne firm formed (lumbering in Roscommon and Crawford Counties, mill at Muskegon)
1876 John W. Blodgett graduated Highland Military Academy, Worcester, Mass.
1878 John W. Blodgett took charge of Blodgett interests in Muskegon
1878 Tillotsen & Blodgett firm formed (Muskegon mill)
1880 Delos A. Blodgett delegate to Republican National Convention
1881 Delos A. Blodgett moved to Grand Rapids
1882 John W. Blodgett took charge of Blodgett & Byrne interests
1885 Blodgett began buying land in Mississippi
1886 John W. Blodgett president of Muskegon Boom Co.
1890 Jennie Blodgett died
1890s Delos A. Blodgett involved in lumber manufacture in Cadillac
1892 Delos A. Blodgett delegate to Republican National Convention
1893 Delos A. Blodgett and Daisy A. Peck married
1893 Blodgett Muskegon basin timber exhausted
1895 John W. Blodgett and Minnie A. Cumnock married
1896 Delos A. Blodgett delegate to Republican National Convention
1900 John W. Blodgett took over all his father's interests
1900 Delos A. Blodgett delegate to Republican National Convention
1900-1912 John W. Blodgett member Republican National Committee
ca. 1905 Blodgett Co., Ltd., formed
1908 Delos A. Blodgett died
1918 Michigan-California Lumber Co. formed
until 1922 John W. Blodgett director of Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago
1925 John W. Blodgett, Jr. became member of business
1931 Minnie Blodgett died
1951 John W. Blodgett died
The collection, although still largely unprocessed, has been grouped into different kinds of records. These include correspondence, business records, maps, and photographs.
Subjects:
Blodgett family.; Business records.; California.; Canada.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Logging--United States.; Lumbering--United States.; Mississippi.; Oregon.; Vancouver Island (B.C.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Banquets.; Blodgett, Delos A., 1825-1908.; Blodgett, John Wood, 1860-1951.; Lumber industry.; Republican National Committee (U.S.); Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.
Subjects - Maps:
Blodgett Company--Maps.; California--Maps.; Clare County (Mich.)--Maps.; Forests and forestry--United States--Maps.; Lake County (Mich.)--Maps.; Logging--United States--Maps.; Logging railroads--United States--Maps.; Louisiana--Maps.; Mecosta County (Mich.)--Maps.; Missaukee County (Mich.)--Maps.; Mississippi--Maps.; Montmorency County (Mich.)--Maps.; Muskegon County (Mich.)--Maps.; Oregon--Maps.; Osceola County (Mich.)--Maps.; Oscoda County (Mich.)--Maps.; Otsego County (Mich.)--Maps.; Roscommon County (Mich.)--Maps.; Vancouver Island (B.C.)--Maps.; Wexford County (Mich.)--Maps.
Contributors:
Blodgett, Delos A., 1825-1908.; Blodgett, John Wood, 1860-1951.; Blodgett, John W., Jr.; Blodgett Company.; Hill-Davis Company.; Michigan-California Lumber Company.; Michigan Timber Company.; Tidewater Timber Company.; Wright-Blodgett Company.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1872-1911 (Box 1)
  - 1901-1908 (Box 2)
  - 1909-1912 (Box 3)
  - 1913-1917 (Box 4)
  - 1916-1917 (Box 5)
  - 1917-1918 (Box 6)
  - 1918-1919 (Box 7)
  - 1919-1921 (Box 8)
  - 1922-1925 (Box 9)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 10)
  - 1926-1928 (Box 11)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 12)
  - 1929 (Box 13)
  - 1929-1933 (Box 14)
  - 1934 also scrapbooks and miscellaneous (Box 33)
  - Personal and miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
- Business records
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 17)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 18)
    continued
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 19)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 20)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 21)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 22)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 23)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 24)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 25)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 26)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 27)
  - Legal papers, bills, receipts, etc. (Box 28)
  - Letter books (Box 29)
    - E.G. Raymond (secretary-treasurer of the Blodgett Co.)
      - 1904-1907 (Box 29)
      - 1908-1910 (Box 29)
      - 1910-1912 (Box 29)
    - P.S. Brumby (Oregon agent) 1903-1909 (Box 29)
    - E. McLennon (Mississippi agent) 1904-1907 (Box 29)
    - Blodgett Co., Ltd.
      - January-July 1907 (Box 29)
      - July-December 1907 (Box 29)
      - December 1907-July 1908 (Box 29)
      - July 1908-March 1909 (Box 30)
      - March-October 1909 (Box 30)
      - October 1909-April 1910 (Box 30)
      - April 1910-February 1911 (Box 30)
      - February-September 1911 (Box 30)
      - September 1911-April 1912 (Box 30)
      - April 1912-January 1913 (Box 30)
    - John W. Blodgett
      - April 1905-March 1907 (Box 31)
      - March 1907-March 1908 (Box 31)
      - March 1908-December 1908 (Box 31)
      - December 1908-January 1910 (Box 31)
      - December 1910-January 1912 (Box 31)
      - January-December 1912 (Box 31)
      - December 1912-January 1913 (Box 31)
    - Wright-Blodgett Co., Ltd.
      - June 1889-February 1902 (Box 32)
      - February 1902-April 1905 (Box 32)
      - February 1911-November 1917 (Box 32)
      - November 1917-December 1921 (Box 32)
  - Journals
    - Volume 1 April 1884-December 1886 (Volume 1)
    - Volume 2 December 1886-August 1888 (Volume 2)
    - Volume 3 September 1888-March 1890 (Volume 3)
    - Volume 4 March 1890-February 1892 (Volume 4)
    - Volume 5 February 1892-January 1894 (Volume 5)
    - Volume 6 January 1894-October 1895 (Volume 6)
    - Volume 7 October 1895-July 1897 (Volume 7)
    - Volume 8 July 1897-March 1899 (Volume 8)
    - Volume 9 March 1899-May 1900 (Volume 9)
    - Volume 10 May 1899-September 1901 (Volume 10)
    - Volume 11 October 1901-December 1902 (Volume 11)
    - Volume 12 January 1903-March 1910 (Volume 12)
    - Volume 33 1919-1934 (Volume 33)
  - Cash books
    - Volume 13 April 1884-December 1890 (Volume 13)
    - Volume 14 December 1890-January 1897 (Volume 14)
    - Volume 15 January 1897-June 1901 (Volume 15)
    - Volume 16 July 1901-December 1902 (Volume 16)
    - Volume 17 January 1903-May 1904 (Volume 17)
    - Volume 32 1931-1934 (Volume 32)
  - Ledgers
    - Volume 18 April 1884-April 1893 (Volume 18)
    - Volume 19 May 1893-April 1902 (Volume 19)
    - Volume 20 May-December 1902 (Volume 20)
    - Volume 21 January 1903-April 1906 (Volume 21)
    - Volume 31 1926-1934 (Volume 31)
  - Miscellaneous
    - volumes. 22-24, Indexes to ledgers (Volume 22)
    - volumes. 22-24, Indexes to ledgers (Volume 23)
    - volumes. 22-24, Indexes to ledgers (Volume 24)
    - Vol 25, Record of Oregon lands 1890s (Volume 25)
      (includes maps; Clatsop, Columbia, Tillamook, and Washington Counties)
    - Volume 26, Record of Mississippi lands 1880s-1890s (Volume 26)
      (includes maps; George, Greene, Jackson, Jefferson Davis, Jones, Lamar, Marion, Pearl River, Perry, Wayne Counties)
    - Volume 27, Land book 1880s (Volume 27)
      (includes maps; Clare, Lake, Mecosta, Missaukee, Osceola, Roscommon, Wexford Counties, Michigan, and Lamar, Marion, Pearl River Counties, Mississippi)
    - Volume 28, Land book 1870s (Volume 28)
      (includes maps; Clare, Crawford, Lake, Mecosta, Missaukee, Montmorency, Muskegon, Osceola, Oscoda, Otsego, Roscommon, Wexford Counties, Michigan)
    - Volume 29, Insurance register (Volume 29)
    - Volume 30, Income tax records 1913-1923 (Volume 30)
    - Volume 34, Memoranda 1932-1934 (Volume 34)
    - Volume 35, Record of land contracts and mortgages (Volume 35)
    - Volume 36, Mississippi contracts 1916-1928 (Volume 36)
    - Volume 37, Piave, Miss., lumber shipment record 1929-1933 (Volume 37)
    - Volume 38, Township plats, Mississippi lands circa 1920 (Volume 38)
      (show timber estimates, Greene, Perry, and Jones Counties)
    - Volume 39, Mississippi lands of John W. Blodgett circa 1935 (Volume 39)
      (includes maps; Greene, Perry, and Jones Counties)
    - Volume 40, Mississippi lands of Minnie C. Blodgett circa 1920-1930 (Volume 40)
    - Volume 41, Mississippi lands of John W. Blodgett 1903-1917 (Volume 41)
      (includes maps; Lamar, Marion, and Pearl River Counties)
    - Volume 42, Michigan lands of Blodgett Co., Ltd. 1891-1908 (Volume 42)
      (includes maps; Benzie, Clare, Kalkaska, Lake, Mecosta, Missaukee, Newaygo, Osceola, Roscommon, Wexford Counties)
    - Volume 43, Mississippi lands of Blodgett Co., Ltd. 1897-1916 (Volume 43)
      (includes maps; George, Greene, Jackson, Jones, Perry, Wayne Counties)
- Maps
  (in blueprint cabinets)
  - California
    - Calaveras County area 1914-1948 (Folder 1)
    - Redwood Creek area 1918-1953 (Folder 2)
  - Louisiana 1898 (Allen, Rapides, Washington Parishes) (Folder 3)
  - Mississippi
    - Jones, Perry, Wayne Counties 1897-1903 (Folder 4)
    - George, Greene, Jackson Counties 1897-1903 (Folder 5)
    - Lamar, Marion, Pearl River Counties 1897-1903 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous 1910-1935 (Folder 7)
  - Oregon
    - Clatsop County 1921-1938 (Folder 8)
    - Linn County 1915-1941 (Folder 9)
    - Tillamook County 1924-1945 (Folder 10)
  - Vancouver Island 1913-1945, undated (Folder 11)
- Photographs
  - Portraits of Delos and John Blodgett; photos of lumber mills, group portraits of the Republican National Committee 1903, 1908 the Grand Rapids Board of Trade, 1905 and a banquet honoring Theodore Roosevelt, 1905 (Folder 12)